建造机器看起来有一种长期的人类兴趣或着迷
There’s been a long-term human interest or fascination in building machines that look
并像我们一样行事。早在18世纪和19世纪，人们就开始建造机器了
and act like we do. Back in the 18th and 19th centuries, people were building machines that
他们称之为Automata，这里展示了一些例子。基本上，他们是
they called Automata, and some examples of them are shown here. Essentially, they’re
非常巧妙的时钟工作机器充满齿轮和凸轮等。
very ingenious, clock-work machines filled with gears and cams and so on.
这位右侧显示的作家起草人的例子能够表演
The example the writer draftsman shown here on the right hand side, was able to perform
非常非常精细的图纸。这里举一个例子，显示了一只绵羊的图画。早一点
very, very elaborate drawings. An example here, a drawing of a sheep is shown. An earlier
而这一类机器的非常着名的例子就是消化鸭子了
and very famous example of machines of this class is the digesting duck and once again
这是一台钟表机。你用这只鸭子做的是用小食物喂它
it is a clock-work machine. What you’d do with this duck is you would feed it with small
它看起来像吃的颗粒，它们会通过消化道
pellets which it would appear to eat and they would pass through the digestive tracts of
鸭子最终排出体外。
the duck and be eventually excreted.
他们能够建造一个看起来像生命一样的机器，它会吃掉它会
They’re able to build a machine that appeared to be life-like, it would eat and it would
排泄。活着的东西的两个重要功能。那个时候，这个
excrete. Two of the important functions of something that is alive. At that time, this
被认为是非常精彩的，技术进步的一个例子，他们是如何做到的
was considered quite wonderful, an example of technological progress, how they were able
制造非常非常逼真的机器。当然，按照今天的标准来看
to build machines that were very, very life-like. Of course by today’s standards, it looks
非常，非常原始，但那时，这是一个了不起的成就。
very, very primitive but at that time, it was an amazing achievement.
现在，设计这个的绅士Vaucanson继续做了一些更有用的事情。他
Now, the gentleman who designed this, Vaucanson, went on to do some more useful things. He
参与丝绸织造过程的自动化。编织技术是
got involved in automating the process of silk weaving. The technology of weaving was
由Jacquard进一步推进，他介绍了控制编织图案的创新
advanced further by Jacquard and he introduced the innovation of controlling the weave pattern
通过一系列打孔木卡。所以，这是一种自动化机器和
by means of a series of punched wooden cards. So, this was a form of automated machine and
它是可编程的。出来的图案取决于打孔的图案
it was programmable. The pattern that came out depended on the patterns of holes punched
在那些木牌里。
in those wooden cards.
CharlesBabbage在怀孕期间接受了打卡控制的概念
The notion of punch card control was picked up by Charles Babbage, when he was conceiving
19世纪后期的机械计算引擎。那时他没有技术
a mechanical computing engine in the late 1800s. At that time he didn't have the technology
实际构建这台机器，但他介绍了一个非常重要的通用概念
to actually build this machine but he introduced the really important notion of a general-purpose
计算引擎及其执行的计算由程序决定。在
computing engine and the computation that it performed is dictated by a program. In
他的情况，输入打孔卡。
his case, input on punched cards.
该机器所体现的思想影响了后来的电子计算设备。为
The ideas embodied in this machine influenced later electronic computing devices. For an
例如，在第二次世界大战期间和该机器制造的ENIAC计算机，
instance, the ENIAC Computer that was built during World War II and from that machine,
我们可以追踪我们每天使用的计算机，我们的笔记本电脑和移动设备
we can trace a lineage to the computers we use every day, in our laptops and in our mobile
当然，手机和计算机是我们今天构建的机器人系统的关键组成部分。
phones, and computers of course, are a critical component of robot systems that we build today.
我们或许可以将机器人视为可以为物理世界做事的计算机。
We can perhaps think of a robot as a computer that can do things to the physical world.
正如我们今天所知，导致机器人技术的另一个非常重要的创新就是这个
The other really important innovation that led to robotics as we know them today is this
第二次世界大战后在美国阿贡国家实验室完成的工作
work that was done after World War II at the Argonne National Laboratory in the United
状态。在那里，他们面临着组装核武器的问题。这需要
States. In there, they were faced by a problem of assembling nuclear weapons. This required
他们处理，操纵放射性物质。这是一项任务
them to handle, to manipulate pieces of material that were radioactive. This was a task that
不能由人类承担，因为它会伤害或杀死那些做过的人
couldn't be undertaken by human beings because it would injure or kill the people who did
那工作。我们需要有机器来处理这种材料，但问题是
that work. We needed to have machines to handle that material instead but the problem was
为了操纵这种放射性物质，我们需要大量的技能和智慧，
that we need a lot of skill and intelligence in order to manipulate this radioactive material,
所以，他们提出了一个名为远程操作的概念。
so, they came up with a concept called teleoperation.
白大衣的人坐在所谓的主操纵臂上
The people in white coats are sitting with what are called the master manipulator arms
所以他们会用手抓住那些武器，然后移动它们。双臂在这里
so they would grab those arms with their hands and they would move them. The arms over here
被称为奴隶武器。它们以模仿动作的方式移动
are referred to as the slave arms. They move in such a way as to mimic the motion of the
主臂。所以，那些正在进行装配和控制大师的人
master arm. So, the people who were doing the assembly work and controlling the master
武器，奴隶武器在远程房间里进行放射性物质的工作。
arms, the slave arms are in a remote room performing work on the radioactive material.
放射性房间发生的事情的视频会传回给人们
Video of what’s going on in the radioactive room is transmitted back to the people doing
与主臂一起工作，这样他们就可以看到电视显示器上发生了什么。他们搬家了
the work with the master arm so they can see what’s happening on a TV monitor. They move
主臂，从属臂同步移动并远程执行任务。这是一种技术
the master arms, the slave arms move in synchronism and perform the task remotely. This is a technique
称为远程操作。它不是真正的机器人。在某些方面，你可以把它想象成一个非常复杂的，
called teleoperation. It’s not really robotic. In some ways, you can think of it as a very-sophisticated,
遥控技术。在这方面完成这项具体任务非常重要
remote-controlled technology. It was really important to achieve this specific task at
阿贡国家实验室。
the Argonne National Laboratory.
该技术是现代制造机器人的重要先驱。我们所做的
This technology is an important precursor to modern manufacturing robots. What we do
我们是在主臂和从臂之间切断导线而不是主导线
is we cut the wire between the master arm and the slave arm and instead of the master
我们将命令发送到从属臂，我们将计算机放在那里。所以，电脑
arm sending the commands to the slave arm, we put a computer there instead. So, the computer
将命令发送到将根据信号移动的从属臂
is sending commands to the slave arm which is going to move in accordance to the signals
走出电脑。当然，计算机是无限可重编程设备
coming out of the computer. Of course, the computer is an infinitely reprogrammable device
因此，我们可以让奴隶臂做任何我们喜欢的事情，现在，那里
so therefore we can make the slave arm do anything that we like at all and now, there
不再涉及任何人类。我们创造了一个机器人。
are no longer any human beings involved. We've created a robot.
也许这个想法最初出现的人是乔治·德沃尔，这位绅士表现出来
And perhaps the person that this idea first occurred to is George Devol, the gentleman shown
在这里，一位多产的美国发明家最近才去世。他有创造的想法
here, a prolific American inventor who died only recently. He had the idea of creating
他称之为Unimation的通用自动化。那就是
what he called universal automation which was contracted to Unimation. That was the
他与JosephEngelberger于1956年创立的公司名称。他们创立了
name of the company that he founded in 1956 with Joseph Engelberger. They founded the
该公司生产最终将在通用汽车公司工作的工业机器人
company to produce industrial robots that would eventually go to work in General Motors
植物。这里展示了1961年安装的第一台机器人。这是什么
plants. The first of their robots which was installed in 1961 is shown here. What this
机器人做的是从压铸机上卸下铸件。
robot did was to unload castings from a die-casting machine.
这是制造业中机器人革命的开始。Unimation公司，
This was the start of the revolution of robots working in the manufacturing industry. Unimation,
公司是第一家制造机器人的公司。他们是先驱者。他们是
Inc. was the first company to build manufacturing robots. They were the pioneers. They’re
不再是商业和现在，有许多公司建立制造业
no longer in business and today, there are many, many companies that build manufacturing
机器人，但他们中的大多数可以追溯他们的祖先，他们的想法，甚至可能追溯到人们
robots, but most of them can trace their ancestry, their ideas or perhaps even the people back
这家小公司成立于1956年，位于美国康涅狄格州。
to this little company founded in 1956 in Connecticut in the United States.